你以为我在玩性虐待吗？
Do you find me sadistic?
知道吗，小乖…
You know, Kiddo...
我相信…
...I'd like to believe...
即使现在你还是很清醒…
...you're aware enough, even now...
知道我不是在和你…
... to know that there's nothing sadistic...
玩性虐待的游戏
...in my actions.
此时…
At this moment...
是我…
...this is me...
最痛苦的时刻
...at my most masochistic.
比尔
Bill.
这是你的骨肉…
It's your ba...
我像是死了，对吧？
Looked dead, didn't I?
不过我没死
Well, I wasn't.
起码我可以说，我是千辛万苦
才捡回这条命的
But it wasn't from lack of trying, I can tell you that.
事实上比尔最后一枪
使我陷入昏迷状态－
Actually, Bill's last bullet put me in a coma -
一场长达四年的昏迷
a coma I was to lie in for four years.
我苏醒之后，就开始了
像电影广告词似的…
When I woke up, I went on what the movie advertisements refer to as
"怒吼疯狂之复仇"
"a roaring rampage of revenge."
我怒吼，我疯狂
I roared, and I rampaged,
我也得到了血腥的满足
and I got bloody satisfaction.
到目前为止，我已经宰了不少人了
I've killed a hell of a lot of people to get to this point,
但是还剩一个没杀
but I've only one more.
最后的一个
The last one.
就是现在我开车去找的这个人
The one I'm driving to right now.
唯一剩下的人
The only one left.
等我到了那里
And when I arrive at my destination,
我将会…"杀死比尔"
I am gonna kill Bill.
片名：(杀死比尔)第二卷
第六章
第六章：双松镇大屠杀
双松镇结婚教堂发生的案子…
The incident that happened at the Two Pines Wedding Chapel
也就是这个故事的起因…
that put this whole gory story into motion
已经成为一个传奇故事
has since become legend.
"双松镇大屠杀"
"Massacre at Two Pines. "
报纸上是这么称呼它的
That's what the newspapers called it.
而当地电视台称之为…
The local TV news called it,
"德州艾帕索市婚礼教堂之惨案"
"The El Paso, Texas Wedding Chapel Massacre. "
怎么发生的，有谁在场…
How it happened, who was there,
死了多少人，是谁杀的…
how many got killed and who killed them -
众说纷纭，莫衷一是
changes depending on who's telling the story.
事实上，惨案根本不是发生在婚礼上
In actual fact, the massacre didn't happen during a wedding at all.
而是婚礼之前的彩排上
It was a wedding rehearsal.
彩排到牧师对新郎说…
Now, when we come to the part where I say,
"你现在可以吻新娘"
你现在可以吻新娘
"You may kiss the bride," you may kiss the bride.
不过别把舌头伸进她嘴巴里
But don't stick your tongue in her mouth.
你朋友们或许会觉得很有趣
This might be funny to your friends,
可是会让你父母难堪
but it would be embarrassing to your parents.
我们会控制自己的，牧师
We'll try to restrain ourselves, Reverend.
你们想好要用哪支曲子了吗？
Y'all got a song?
"温柔地爱我"如何？
这首歌我会
How 'bout "Love Me Tender"? I can play that.
- 好啊
- 嗯
- Sure. - Yeah.
"温柔地爱我"，这曲子很好
"Love Me Tender" would be great.
如弗斯…就是他
Rufus - he's the man.
如弗斯…你当初是替谁伴奏来着？
Rufus, who was that that you used to play for?
如弗斯・汤玛斯
Rufus Thomas.
Rufus Thomas. Rufus Thomas.
我曾加入"哲欧"，"流浪着"
和"游走"乐团
I was a Drell. I was a Drifter. I was a Coaster.
也曾是"街头小子"
和"巴可"的一份子
I was part of the Gang. I was a Barkay.
只要他们来德州
我就和他们一起演奏
If they come through Texas, I done played with 'em.
如弗斯…就是你啦
Rufus - he's the man.
- 我还忘了什么吗？
- 我想想…
- Have I forgotten anything? - Um...
嗯…哦…对了…
你忘了安排坐位了
Oh yes, you forgot, uh, the seating arrangements.
- 谢谢你，老妈
- 嗯
- Thank you, Mother. - Yes.
按照我们的惯例…
Now, the way we normally do this -
我们有新娘这一边
还有新郎这一边
we have the bride's side, and then we have the groom's side.
不过新娘这边没人出席
But since the bride ain't got nobody comin',
而新郎这边又有太多人要来…
and the groom's got far too many people comin'...
对呀，还有人大老远
从奥克拉荷马州来呢！
Well, yeah, they're comin' all the way from Oklahoma.
对呀…
Right...
那么…我觉得可以…
Well, I don't see no problem with...
让新郎这边的人
也去坐到新娘那边
...the groom's side sharing the bride's side.
- 你说呢，老妈？
- 我不反对
- Do you, Mother? - I don't have a problem with that.
但是…
But, uh...
亲爱的，如果你那边
也有人来就更好了
Honey, you know, it would be good if you had somebody come.
这表示…他们也祝福你？
You know, as a sign of good faith?
可是，我真的没有亲朋好友…
Well, I don't have anybody...
除了汤米和这些朋友
...except for Tommy and my friends.
- 连家人都没有吗？
- 嗯…很快就会有了
- You have no family? - Well, I'm workin' on changing that.
哈蒙尼太太，我们就是
这位天使需要的所有的人了
Mrs. Harmony, we're all the family this little angel's ever gonna need.
我有点不舒服
肚里的小ㄚ头让我很难受
I'm not feeling very well, and this bitch is starting to piss me off.
你们继续聊，我出去透口气儿
So while y'all blather on, I'm gonna go outside and get some air.
好了…牧师…对不起…
OK. Um, uh, Reverend, sorry, uh...
- 她要出去透透气儿
- 是的，以她现在的身体状况，…
- She's gonna go out and get some air. - Yeah. Given her delicate condition...
几分钟就好，她没事儿的
She just needs a few minutes to get it together. She'll be OK.
哦…
Right...
哈，小乖
Hello, Kiddo.
- 你是怎么找到我的？
- 这还用说
- How did you find me? - I'm the man.
你在这儿干嘛？
What are you doin' here?
我在干嘛？
What am I doin'?
哦…
Well...
我刚才在吹箫
...moment ago I was playin' my flute.
现在…
At this moment...
我这双老眼正看着
我所见过最迷人的新娘
...I'm lookin' at the most beautiful bride these old eyes have ever seen.
- 你为什么会在这儿？
- 看你最后一眼
- Why are you here? - Last look.
- 你会好好的吗？
- 我这辈子从来没做过好人
- Are you gonna be nice? - I've never been nice in my whole life.
不过我会尽量表现出…和善
But I'll do my best to be sweet.
哦
Hmm.
我总是告诉你…
I always told you...
你和善的一面是你最好的一面
...your sweet side is you best side.
我想这大概就是为什么
你是唯一见过我和善面的人吧
I guess that's why you're the only one who's ever seen it.
- 瞧…你已经大腹便便了
- 嗯
- So you got a bun in the oven. - Hmm.
- 我怀孕了
- 哇
- I'm knocked up. - Jeez, Louise.
你的那个小伙子还真不浪费时间啊
That young man of yours sure doesn't believe in wasting time, does he?
你见过汤米没有？
Have you seen Tommy?
- 那个穿燕尾礼服的吗？
- 对
- Big guy in the tux? - Yes.
那我见过了
Then I saw him.
我挺喜欢他的发型
I like his hair.
你答应过要好好的喔
You promised you'd be nice.
我说过会尽力而为
算不上是承诺吧
No, I said I'd do my best. That's hardly a promise.
不过你是对的
But you're right.
你未来的夫婿是干哪行的？
What does your young man do for a living?
他在艾帕索这儿
开了家二手唱片行
He owns a used record store here in El Paso.
- 喔…是音乐爱好者，对吧？
- 他热爱音乐
- Ah. Music lover, eh? - He's fond of music.
我们也是啊？
Aren't we all?
那你最近干什么活儿维生呢？
And what are you doing for a J-O-B these days?
我在唱片行里打工
I work in the record store.
啊…原来
Aso.
突然间一切都清楚了
It all suddenly seems so clear.
- 你喜欢那份工作吗？
- 嗯，我非常喜欢，你这聪明鬼
- Do you like it? - Yeah. I like it a lot, smartass.
我可以成天听音乐…
I get to listen to music all day...
聊音乐. 真的酷得很
...talk about music all day. It's really cool.
对我的小女儿来说
这是个合适的成长环境
It's gonna be a great environment for my little girl to grow up in.
你是拿那种刀头舐血
杀人掳掠的活儿来比吧？
As opposed to jetting around the world, killing human beings, and being paid vast sums of money?
正是
Precisely.
那么，老朋友…
Well, my old friend...
咱们各走各的路
...to each his own.
不过，先把琐事放一边…
However, all cockblockery aside...
我非常期待见见那小伙子
I am looking forward to meeting your young man.
我其实很在意我的女人
到底嫁给了谁
I happen to be, more or less, particular whom my gal marries.
- 你也要来参加婚礼吗？
- 除非能安排我坐在新娘这边
- You want to come to the wedding? - Only if I can sit on the bride's side.
你会发现我这边有点冷清的
You'll find it a bit lonely on my side.
你身边一向很冷清
Your side always was a bit lonely.
但我不会坐其它地方
But I wouldn't sit anywhere else.
你知道…
You know...
我昨晚有个美梦，梦到了你…
...I had the loveliest dream about you...
哦，汤米过来了！
记得叫我爱琳
Oh, here's Tommy! Call me Arlene.
- 你一定是汤米！
- 嗯
- You must be Tommy! - Uh-huh.
爱琳跟我说了很多关于你的事
Arlene's told me so much about you.
- 宝贝，你没事吧？
- 哦，我很好
- Honey, you OK? - Oh, I'm fine.
汤米，让我来介绍我父亲
Tommy, I'd like you to meet my father.
哇，老天！
Oh, my God!
哇，老天！ 真是太好了！
Oh, my God, this is great!
我真高兴认识你，先生
哦…不对…爸爸
I'm so glad to meet you, sir... uh, Dad.
我叫比尔
The name's Bill.
哦，真高兴能认识你，比尔
Well, it's great to meet you... Bill.
- 爱琳跟我说你不能来.
- 给你个惊喜
- Arlene told me you couldn't make it. - Surprise.
我老爸就是这样
总是出人意料
That's my pop for ya. Always full of surprises.
没错啦，说到"出人意料"…
Well, in the surprise department...
真是有其父必有其女
...the apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
- 你什么时候到的？
- 刚到
- When did you get in? - Just now.
- 直接从澳大利亚来？
- 当然
- Did you come straight from Australia? - Of course.
爸，我告诉汤米，你在澳洲挖银矿
Daddy, I told Tommy that you were in Perth mining for silver, and...
没人找得到你
...no one could reach you.
很幸运的是，这次不一样啦
Lucky for us all, that's not the case.
我说…
So...
你们这是干嘛呢？
我只听过平装彩排
What's this all about? I've heard of wedding rehearsals,
但不曾听说盛装彩排
but I don't believe I've ever heard of a wedding dress rehearsal before.
我们想说
We thought,
婚纱礼服这么贵
只穿一次太可惜了
"Why pay so much money for a dress you're only gonna wear once?"
特别是爱琳穿上它
是如此的美丽
Especially when Arlene looks so goddamn beautiful in it.
所以我们打算物尽其用
So, I think we're gonna try to get all the mileage we can out of it.
不是说…新郎在婚礼前
看到新娘穿礼服是不好的预兆
Isn't it supposed to be bad luck for the groom to see the bride in her wedding dress before the ceremony?
我是想，活着就该经历些风浪吧
Well, I guess I just believe in living dangerously.
我恰巧懂你的意思
I know just what you mean.
孩子
有些人还有事呢
Son. Some of us have places to be.
就是说嘛
Sure do.
我们还得再排练一次
还是请你去坐…
Look, we got to go through this one more time. So, why don't you have a s...
哦，天哪，我是怎么啦？
你应该牵着新娘进场才对
Oh, my God. What am I thinking? You should give her away!
汤米，爹地不太喜欢这样
Tommy, that's not exactly Daddy's cup of tea.
我想他还是…
I think Father would be much more comfortable
- 和其他来宾坐一起会比较自在
- 哦. 真的吗？
- sitting with the rest of the guests. - Hmm. Really?
要求是过分了
That's asking a lot.
哦，好吧，那就算了
Oh. OK. Well, forget it.
那今晚吃个饭庆祝一下如何？
But how about we go out to dinner tonight to celebrate?
我请客才行
Only on the condition that I pay for everything.
说定了. 我们得彩排了
Deal. We got to do this now.
- 我能观礼吗？
- 当然，请坐吧
- Can I watch? - Absolutely. Have a seat.
- 新娘席在哪边？
- 就在这儿
- Which is the bride's side? - Right over here.
新郎的妈，开始吧！
Mother, here we go!
现在，孩子，关于誓言的部分…
Now son, about them vows...
比尔…
Bill...
- 我只想…
- 你不欠我什么
- I just want... - You don't owe me a damn thing.
如果他就是你要的男人…
If he's the man you want...
那就去他身边吧
...then go stand by him.
- 我漂亮吗？
- 哦，当然
- Do I look pretty? - Oh, yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
搞什么鬼呀？
What the hell?
不要！ 比尔！
No! Bill!
你是说她杀了88个保镳
才杀到尾连面前？
You tellin' me she cut her way through 88 bodyguards before she got to O-Ren?
不是刚好88人啦
Nah, there wasn't really 88 of 'em.
他们只是自称"疯狂88人帮"
They just called themselves "The Crazy 88"
- 为什么？
- 我怎知
- How come? - I don't know.
也许他们觉得这名号很酷吧
I guess they thought it sounded cool.
那他们是怎么死在她的半藏刀下？
Anyhow, they all fell under her Hanzo sword.
- 她有把半藏刀？
- 他铸了一把给她
- She got a Hanzo sword? - He made one for her.
他不是发过毒誓不再铸刀了吗？
Didn't he swear a blood oath to never make another sword?
似乎他破了誓
It would appear he has broken it.
日本鬼子不是很记仇的吗？
Them Japs sure know how to hold a grudge, don't they?
还是…
Or maybe...
你会让人想起旧仇
...you just tend to bring that out in people.
恕我冒昧的问个蠢问题…
I know this is a ridiculous question before I ask it,
你刀上的功夫还没落下吧？
but you haven't, by any chance, kept up with your... swordplay?
我，呃…
I, um...
几年前我就把刀当掉了
I pawned that years ago.
你把服部半藏的刀当了！？
You hocked a Hattori Hanzo sword?
嗯
Yep.
是无价之宝啊！
It was priceless.
在艾帕索算不上什么宝啦
Well, not in El Paso, it ain't.
我在艾帕索当了250块钱
In El Paso, I got me $250 for it.
我在上空舞厅当保镳，比尔
I'm a bouncer in a titty bar, Bill.
如果她想动手，只要去那儿
随便找个茬，咱们就能打起来了
If she wants to fight with me, all she's got to do is come down to the club and start some shit, and we'll be in a fight.
我知道我们很久没聊聊了
I know we haven't spoken in some time,
最后一次聊天也闹的不愉快
and the last time we spoke wasn't the most pleasant,
但是你不能再生我的气了
but you've got to get over being mad at me,
得开始担心她了
and start becoming afraid of (bleep),
因为她要来找你，她来是要你的命
because she is coming, and she's coming to kill you.
没有我的帮助，她一定成功
And unless you accept my assistance, I have no doubt she will succeed.
我不会逃避我的罪过
也不会逃避我应得的报应
I don't dodge guilt, and I don't Jew out of paying my comeuppance.
我们难道不能忘掉往事？
Can't we just... forget the past?
那个女人…
That woman...
是应该报仇
...deserves her revenge.
同时…
And...
我们也的确该死
...we deserve to die.
但是，换句话说…
But then again...
她也该死
...so does she.
所以我说…
So I guess...
咱们走着瞧吧
...we'll just see.
行吗？
Won't we?
第七章
第七章：宝拉休兹的孤坟
又迟到了
Late again.
巴德，你没时间观念吗？
Budd, can't you tell time?
老兄，还没人上门呢
There ain't nobody in here, man.
- 是巴德？
- 对
- Is that Budd? - Yeah.
叫他给我滚过来
Tell him to get his fucking ass back here!
好
OK.
巴德，赖瑞有话跟你说
Budd, Larry'd like a word with ya.
吸一口，你就浑然忘我了，宝贝
Take a hit. Be somebody, baby.
你找我？
You looking for me?
我不知道你以前
在哪家洗车厂打工
I don't know what car wash you worked before you came here
迟到20分钟还让你大摇大摆的进来
不过肯定不是我的
that let you stroll in 20 minutes late, but it wasn't owned by me
- 不过我真他妈的有间家洗车厂
- 要我回避吗？
- and I own a fuckin' car wash. - Do you want me to leave?
不，别走，我要你坐着等
No, I don't want you to leave. I want you to sit and wait.
瑞赖…
Larry...
外面没有客人，所以…
...there ain't nobody out there, so...
"外面没有客人，赖瑞."
"There's nobody out there, Larry."
你想说啥？
What's your point?
- 这儿用不着你了？
- 我是说…
- That you're not needed here? - My point is...
我是说…我是个保镳
而现在外面又没人闹事啊
...I'm the bouncer, and there ain't nobody out there to bounce.
你是说…
You saying that the reason...
你没干我付钱给你干的活儿
是因为没活可干？
...that you're not doing the job that I'm... paying you to do is that you don't have a job to do?
- 不是…
- 你是这个意思吗？
- No... - Is that what you're saying?
你到底想要我相信什么？
What are you trying to convince me of, exactly?
相信你像这里的屁眼一样
是个没用的废物吗？
That you're as useless as an asshole right here?
猜猜我怎么想，老兄？
Well, guess what, buddy?
他妈的，我还真的被你说服了
I think... you just fucking convinced me.
咱们看看日历吧
Let's go to the calendar.
看日历咯
It's calendar time.
看巴德的值班表喔
Calendar time for Buddy.
- 好. 你明天有班吗？
- 有
- OK. You working tomorrow? - Yeah.
没有，你明天没班
你根本不知道哪天有班
Mm. No, you're n... You don't even know what fucking day you work.
看这儿，明天你没班
Here. You're not working tomorrow.
周三才有
这儿，看到了吧
You're working Wednesday. Here you are. There you go.
- 周四有班吗？
- 有
- Workin' Thursday? - Yeah.
我说没有
星期五
I don't think so. Friday.
我说…这有你的名字
I d... There's your name.
- 你说了算
- 这里以前有你的名字，懂吗？
- If you say so. - There used to be your name. OK?
- 星期六. 以前有你的名字
- 哦
- Saturday. There used to be your name. - Oh.
呃，星期一…
Uh, Monday...
瞧. 这样如何？
Here. How about that?
现在的年轻人只认得钱
其他什么都不懂
Fuckin' with your cash is the only thing you kids seem to understand. OK?
你现在回家等我打电话给你
Now, I want you to go home till I call you.
等我打给你
Till I call you.
走之前去找洛姬
她有事情给你做
Before you leave, talk to Rocket. She's got a job for you to do.
还有…
And...
那个帽子
...the hat.
那个蠢帽子
That fuckin' hat.
那蠢…
That fucking...
我跟你说过多少次
How many times have I told you,
不准你在这里戴那个蠢帽子
don't wear that fucking hat here? How many?
客人也有戴帽子呀
Customers wear hats.
我不是客人的老板
Well, I'm not the boss of the customers.
我是你的老板
所以我告诉你…
I'm the boss of you. And I'm telling you...
我要你把那顶
又蠢又驴的帽子留在家里
...that I want you to keep that shit-kicker hat at home.
嗨，巴德，亲爱的
马桶又坏了
Yeah. Budd, honey, uh, the toilet is at it again.
粪水流满地.
There's shitty water all over the floor.
知道了，洛姬
OK... Rocket.
- 我会打扫干净的
- 嗯
- I'll clean it up. - Mm-hmm.
(% ''A Satisfied Mind''by Johnny Cash)
# 曾经多少次 #
@ How many times
# 你听人说过 #
@ Have you heard someone say,
# 如果我像他一样富有 #
@ "If I had his money,
# 就能做我想做的事 #
@ I could do things my way"
# 但他们却不知 #
@ But little they know
# 很难找出 #
@ That it's so hard to find
# 十个富人中 #
@ One rich man in ten
# 有一个知足的人 #
@ With a satisfied mind
# 我也曾拥有 #
@ Once I was wading
# 财富与名望 #
@ In fortune and fame
# 所有我梦想的一切 #
@ Everything that I dreamed for
# 人生所需我都曾拥有 #
@ To get a start in life's game
# 突然之间 #
@ Then suddenly it happened
# 我变得一文不名 #
# 但是我现在却更富有… #
@ I lost every dime, but I'm richer...
# 曾经多少次 #
@ How many times
# 你听人说过 #
@ Have you heard someone say...
现在…
Now...
你可冷静下来了吧？
...that gentled you down some, didn't it?
对
Yep.
还没哪个坏蛋的奶子上
有双份的岩盐散弹
Ain't nobody a badass with a double dose of rock salt dug deep in her tits.
哪个坏蛋也没…
像你的奶子一样…
Not havin'... tits...
漂亮…
...as fine...
而且和你的一样大
...or as big as yours,
我难以想像那打在身上有多疼
I can't even imagine how bad that shit must sting.
然而…
Yet...
我也不想知道
...I don't want to, neither.
我赢了
I win.
比尔
Bill.
猜成我哥哥了，臭婊子
Wrong brother, ya hateful bitch.
- 巴德？
- 答对啦
- Budd. - Bingo.
是啥事让我有幸接到你的电话？
And to what do I owe this dubious pleasure?
我刚逮到了那个
从没被逮过的女牛仔
I just caught me the cowgirl ain't never been caught.
- 你宰了她吗？
- 没，我还没
- Did you kill her? - Well, not yet, I ain't.
我着实给了她一枪岩盐弹
I shot her full of rock salt.
她现在乖的不得了
我随时可以拿个石头了结她
She's so gentle right now, I could perform her coup de grace with a rock.
废话少说…
Anywho...
猜猜…我现在手里拿什么？
Guess what I'm holdin' in my hand right now?
什么？
What?
一把全新的服部半藏刀
A brand spankin' new Hattori Hanzo sword.
跟你说，艾儿
And I'm here to tell ya, Elle,
- 这才叫"锋利"呢！
- 多少钱？
-...that's what I call sharp. - How much?
很难说…这是个…无价之宝
Oh, that's hard to say, bein' that it's... priceless and all.
开价吧？
What's the terms?
明天一早你这瘦皮猴…
You get your bony ass down here first thing in the morning...
送一百万捆好的现金过来…
...with a million dollars in folding cash...
我就给你这把
人所能造出最好的刀
...and I'll give you the greatest sword ever made by a man.
你觉得如何呀？
Now, how do you like the sound of that?
听起来咱们像是成交了
Sounds like we got a deal.
- 一个条件
- 什么？
- One condition. - What?
让她受尽苦头
直到咽下最后一口气
She must suffer to her last breath.
这么嘛…
Well...
亲爱的艾儿…
That, Elle darlin'...
我几乎敢打包票
...I can pretty much damn well guarantee.
那么明早见啦…百万富翁
Then I'll see you in the mornin', millionaire.
好的
All right.
醒醒咯，醒醒咯
Wakey, wakey.
早餐的蛋与腌肉
Eggs and bakey.
完工了！
I'm done!
拉我出坑！
Get me outta this hole!
好的很
Good.
哇，看看那双眼
Whoa, look at those eyes.
这婊子一定气疯了
This bitch is furious.
我说的没错吧
What did I tell ya?
她是不是你
见过最性感的金发尤物？
Is she the cutest little blond pussy you ever saw?
还是…她就是你
见过最性感的金发尤物？
Or... is she the cutest little blond pussy you ever saw?
我见过更棒的
I seen better.
你有遗言吗？
You got anything to say?
白人女子称之为"无言的抗议"
White women call this "the silent treatment."
咱们得让她们相信
咱们可不喜欢这样
And we let 'em think we don't like it.
你抬脚，我抬头
You grab the feet, I'll get the head.
小蠕虫，看到这个吗？
Wiggle worm, you see this?
看到了，对吧？
You see it, don't ya?
那是一罐催泪瓦斯
That's a can of Mace.
今晚你马上就要入土了
You're goin' underneath the ground tonight.
就这么简单
And... that's all there is to it.
我想把你埋了…
I wanna bury ya.
我想把你…
I was gonna bury ya...
和这个一起埋了
...with this.
但是如果你不安份点儿
But if you're gonna act like a horse's ass...
我就把他妈的一整罐
直喷到你眼珠子上
...I'm gonna spray this whole goddamn can right in your eyeballs!
会把你眼珠子都给烧出来
I'll burn 'em right outta your fuckin' head.
然后你就瞎了…
Then you're gonna be blind...
烧了你…
...and burnin'...
再活埋
...and buried alive.
你自己选，妹子
Now, what's it gonna be, sister?
算你聪明
That's a wise decision.
这一定会伤透了我老哥哥的心
This is for breakin' my brother's heart.
第八章
第八章：白眉严教
从前…
Once upon a time...
在中国…
...in China...
据说大约在…
...some believe around the year...
公元1003年
...one double aught-three,
白莲教掌门白眉道长走在街上
head priest of the White Lotus Clan, Pai Mei, was walking down a road...
思索着只有白眉这种绝世高手
才会思索的问题
...contemplating whatever it is that a man of Pai Mei's infinite powers would contemplate
换句话说就是
天晓得他在想什么
which is another way of saying, "Who knows?"
有个少林和尚迎面走来
when a Shaolin monk appeared on the road,
向他迎面走来
traveling in the opposite direction.
就在他们擦肩而过时…
As the monk and the priest crossed paths...
白眉…
...Pai Mei...
白眉几乎是高深莫测的
向他友善的点了点头
...in a practically unfathomable display of generosity, gave the monk the slightest of nods.
这点头礼…
The nod...
却没得到回应
...was not returned.
到底是和尚是有意羞辱白眉
Now, was it the intention of the Shaolin monk to insult Pai Mei?
还是他没注意到对方的社交礼仪
Or did he just fail to see the generous social gesture?
和尚真正的意思无从得知
The motives of the monk remain unknown.
唯一知道的是…
What is known...
后果
...were the consequences.
第二天早上白眉来到了少林寺
The next morning, Pai Mei appeared at the Shaolin temple...
要求掌门方丈…
...and demanded of the temple's head abbot
自刎谢罪
that he offer Pai Mei his neck to repay the insult.
起先方丈想和安抚他
The abbot, at first, tried to console Pai Mei.
却发现白眉…
Only to find Pai Mei was...
难消怒气
...inconsolable.
接下来…
So began...
白莲教就血洗少林
全寺60僧众无一幸免
...the Massacre of the Shaolin Temple, and all sixty of the monks inside, at the fists of the White Lotus.
然后…传说从此开始…
And... so began the legend...
白眉的五指穿心掌
...of Pai Mei's Five-Point-Palm Exploding-Heart Technique.
- 五指穿心掌到底是啥？
- 非常简单…
And what, pray tell, is the Five-Point-Palm
- Exploding-Heart Technique? - Quite simply,
武学中最致命的一招
the deadliest blow in all of martial arts.
他以五指击你…
He hits you with his fingertips...
五指不等的内力击在你身上…
...at five different pressure points on your body...
然后让你自己逃走
...and then lets you walk away.
但是你在五步之内…
But once you've taken five steps...
穿心…
...your heart explodes inside your body...
倒地而死
...and you fall to the floor, dead.
- 他把这招传给你了吗
- 没有
- Did he teach you that? - No.
他的五指穿心掌从不传人
He teaches no one the Five-Point-Palm Exploding-Heart Technique.
说到这儿…
Now...
我最喜欢你的一点就是…
...one of the things I've always liked about you...
小乖…
...Kiddo...
你看起来比实际的年龄更聪明
...is you appear wise beyond your years.
让我给你这聪明人一点忠告:
So, allow me to impart a word to the wise:
无论如何…
Whatever...
不管白眉说什么，你都得服从
...whatever Pai Mei says, obey.
即使你短暂地露出些许不敬的眼神
他立刻把你眼珠子挖出来
If you flash him, even for an instant, a defiant eye, he'll pluck it out.
如果你的美式骄傲触怒了他…
And if you throw any American sass his way...
他会把你脊椎
和脖子像小树枝一般地劈断
...he'll snap your back and your neck like they were twigs.
那你就成为一个故事了
And that will be the story of you.
他答应收你为徒了
He'll accept you as his student.
- 你怎么啦？
- 没事儿
- What happened to you? - Nothin'.
- 和他动手了？
- 朋友间过个招罢了
- Get in a fight? - Friendly contest.
他怎么会答应收我的？
Why did he accept me?
因为他已经很老很老了
Because he's a very, very, very old man.
和其他老不死的王八蛋一样…
And like all rotten bastards...
他愈老就愈寂寞.
...when they become old, they get lonely.
年纪改不了他的脾气
Which has no effect on their dispositions,
但也让他学到了，有个伴儿的重要
but it does teach them the value of company.
哇赛
Whew. Oh.
光是瞧这些台阶，我腿就软了
Just seein' those steps again makes me ache.
以后你挑着水桶上上下下的
可有你乐的啦
You're gonna have a lot of fun carrying buckets of water up and down that fucker.
我何时能再见到你？
When will I see you again?
就像我最喜欢的70年代
一首黑人灵歌的歌名
That's the title of my favorite soul song of the seventies.
- 啥？
- 没什么
- What? - Nothin'.
等他说你可以出师时
When he tells me you're done.
你想会是何时？
When do you think that might be?
亲爱的，那全看你自己了
That, my dearest, depends entirely on you.
记住，切勿讥讽，切勿顶撞
Now remember, no sarcasm, no backtalk.
起码头一两年里
At least not for the first year or so.
你得给他时间来
慢慢让你进入状况
You're gonna have to let him warm up to you.
他讨厌白人，藐视美国人
He hates Caucasians, despises Americans,
更不喜欢女人
and has nothing but contempt for women.
所以像你这种情行
得多花点儿时间了
So in your case... it might take a little while.
再见啦
- Adios.
师父…
Master...
你的汉语好差
我一个字也听不懂
Your Mandarin is lousy.
而且好刺耳！
It causes my ears discomfort. You bray like an ass!
我没要你说话，你就别说
You are not to speak unless spoken to.
你的汉语好呢
还是你的广东话好？
Is it too much to hope -- you understand Cantonese?
我的日语很好…
I speak Japanese very well--
我没问你日本话
也没问你蒙古话
I didn't ask if you speak Japanese --
我问你会不会说广东话？
I asked if you understand Cantonese?
一点点
A little.
你是来学武的，不是学讲话
You are here to learn the mysteries of Kung Fu, not linguistics.
如果你不懂汉语
If you can't understand me --
就像狗一样
I will communicate with you like I would a dog.
我会斥喝你，命令你，用棍打你！
When I yell, when I point, when I beat you with my stick!
你的师父是不是比尔？
Bill is your master, is he not?
是的
Yes, he is.
你师傅说过你曾经学过武术
Your master tells me -- you're not entirely unschooled.
你学过些什么？
What training do you possess?
我精通虎鹤拳
I am proficient in Tiger-Crane Style,
更精通日本武士道剑术
and I am more than proficient in the exquisite art of the Samurai sword.
哼～日本剑道
开什么玩笑！
The exquisite art of the Samurai sword. Don't make me laugh!
你所谓的剑道不值个屁
你就更加笨
Your so-called exquisite art, is only fit for --
你居然敢正视我
Japanese fat heads!
看你的脾气都可以学武
你觉得本道的功夫跟你比如何？
Your anger amuses me. Do you believe you are my match?
不知
No.
你知道本道会杀人吗？
Are you aware I kill at will?
知道
Yes.
那么你是想死？
Is it your wish to die?
不
No.
傻瓜
Then you must be stupid...
真是傻瓜
Then you must be stupid...so stupid.
本道好想看看你有多傻
Rise, and let me look at your ridiculous face.
起身
Rise.
亏你还学过虎鹤拳
刚才走了一百来台阶就在喘了
So my pathetic friend... Is there anything that you can do well?
我看你不单是傻
What's the matter?
身体也很虚啊
Cat got your tongue?
喔，对了，你会说日本话
-- Oh yes, you speak Japanese.
我最恨日本人！
I despise the Goddamn Japs!
去兵器架那边
Go to that rack.
拔那把剑
Remove the sword.
我要看下你的武功有多深
Let's see how good you really are.
出招.
If...
如果我输给你的话
...you land a single blow,
我干脆拜你为师
I'll bow down and call you master.
你看到我的功夫了吧
试我的脚法
From here you can get an excellent view of my foot.
你的剑术…只是一般入门的水平
Your swordsmanship -- is amateur at best.
残废也比你强
Your so-called kung-fu -- is really -- quite pathetic.
再来啊！
废物
我已经给你机会显示一下你的武功
我看到了
I asked you to demonstrate -- what you know -- and you did...
你一点都不会
Not a goddamn thing!
现在我要你以虎鹤拳
和我的鹰爪拳比试一下
Let's see your Tiger Crane -- match my Eagle's Claw.
你和其他美国女人一样
Like all Yankee women...
只知道在餐馆点菜，花男人的钱
...all you can do is order in restaurants and spend a man's money.
痛吗？ 我问你呢？
Excruciating -- isn't it?
痛！
Yes!
你相不相信我…
If it was my wish...
随时能砍下你的手臂
...I could chop your arm off.
不要！
No, please don't!
你相不相信我想怎样就怎样
It's my arm now. I can do what I please.
如果你不想我砍你的手…动手！
If you can stop me -- I suggest you try.
我不行
I can't.
打不过吧
Because you're helpless?
对
Yes.
你以前试过这种滋味吗？
Have you ever felt this before?
没有
No.
你的功夫和我比，简直是班门弄斧
Compared to me -- you're as helpless as a worm fighting an eagle?
是的！！！
YES!!!
现在开始
THAT'S THE BEGlNNlNG!
你想不想学
我刚才和你打的这套拳？
Is it your wish to possess this kind of power?
想！
Yes!
从明天开始你要练武
Your training will begin -- tomorrow.
记住
你的手臂属于我…
Since your arm now belongs to me...
我会将它练得结实
...I want it strong.
你能不能做到像我这样？
Can you do that?
可以，不过还差你一节
I can, but not that close.
那就是不行了！
Then you can't do it.
如果敌人离你的身体只有三寸…
What if your enemy -- is three inches in front of you...
你怎么对付他？
...What do you do then...
抱头鼠窜…
...Curl into a ball...
还是用拳打穿他？
...or do you put your FlST through him?
现在开始
Now begin.
练拳头不应该是你怕木头
It's the wood that should fear your hand --
应该是木头怕你
-- not the other way around.
你之所以打不穿木头
No wonder you can't do it -- you acquiesce to defeat --
是因为你用手之前已经认输了
-- before you even begin.
如果你像狗一样吃东西
If you want to eat like a dog...
我就让你像狗一样住外面
You can live and sleep outside like a dog.
如果你想像人一样的话
If you want to live and sleep like a human...
把筷子拿起来
...pick up those sticks.
快，你混蛋
Come on, you bitch.
好，白眉
OK, Pai Mei.
我来了
Here I come.
请给我一杯水？
May I have a glass of water, please?
第九章
第九章：艾儿和我
- 原来那就是德州式葬礼？
- 对
-Sothat's a Texas funeral? - Yep.
我不得不承认你还真行，巴德
I have to give it to ya, Budd.
这种死法还真凄惨
That's a pretty fucked up way to die.
她墓碑上是什么名字？
What's the name on the grave she's buried under?
宝…
Paula...
休兹
...Schultz.
能看看那把刀吗？
Can I look at the sword?
我的钱就在那红箱子里，对吧？
That's my money right there in that red bag, isn't it?
没错
It sure is.
那好，刀是你的啦
Well then, it's your sword now.
那么，这就是那把半藏的刀咯！
(blender whirring)
你刚说啥？
What's that you said?
这就是服部半藏铸的刀？
So this is a Hattori Hanzo sword?
没错，就是半藏的刀
That's a Hanzo sword, all right.
比尔告诉我
你曾经也有一把他的刀
Bill tells me you once had one of these of your own.
对，曾经
Yeah, once.
真的？ 这把和那把比如何？
Yeah? How does this one compare to that?
如果你要拿半藏的刀去比…
If you're gonna compare a Hanzo sword...
那么其他所有的刀…
...you compare it to every other sword ever made -
都不是服部半藏铸的
wasn't made - by Hattori Hanzo.
给…大口喝吧
Here you go. Wrap your lips around that.
我说…
So...
你是什么感受？
...which "R" are you filled with?
什么意思？
What?
有人说…
They say...
老人的头号杀手就是退休
...the number one killer... of old people... is retirement.
如果他们还有未竟的事
就得活得久一点去完成
People got a job to do, they tend to live a little bit longer so they can do it.
我一直认为…
I've always figured that...
战士和敌人…
...warriors and their enemies...
有着同样的关系
...share the same relationship.
现在战场上你没有敌人可杀了
So now that you're not gonna have to face your enemy no more on the battlefield...
所以你是什么感受？
...which "R" ya filled with?
轻松…
Relief...
还是婉惜？
...or regret?
- 都有点
- 放屁
- A little bit of both. - Horseshit.
我相信你两种感受都有
I'm sure you do feel a little bit of both.
但我肯定其中一种比另以种多
But I know damn well that you feel one more than you feel the other.
问题是…哪个多点？
And the question was: Which one is it?
婉惜
Regret.
你知道她早晚她会取代你的地位
You know, you gotta hand it to the ol' girl.
我从没看过有谁
能像她那样使比尔着迷
I never saw anybody buffalo Bill the way she buffaloed Bill.
比尔认为她很聪明
Bill thought she was so damn smart.
我试图告诉他…
And I tried to tell him...
她只能算金发美女中比较聪明的
...she was just smart for a blond.
多谢
Thanks a bunch.
哦…对不起.巴德
I'm sorry, Budd.
我太失礼了，对吧？
That was rude of me, wasn't it?
巴德，我给你介绍
这是我的朋友…黑曼巴蛇
Budd, I'd like to introduce my friend, the black mamba.
这是黑曼巴；这是巴德
Black mamba, this is Budd.
我选中这小东西之前
You know, before I picked that little fella up,
在网上查过它的资料
I looked him up on the lnternet.
黑曼巴真是个神奇的动物
Fascinating creature, the black mamba.
听好咯:
Listen to this:
"在非洲，是这么说的…
"ln Africa, the saying goes,
"在原野上，大象能要你的命
豹能要你的命
"'ln the bush, an elephant can kill you, a leopard can kill you,
"黑曼巴蛇也能要你的命
但是只有黑曼巴…
"'and a black mamba can kill you. But only with the mamba,
"自开天辟地以来
能确定让人致命
"and this has been true in Africa since the dawn of time, is death sure.'
因此它被认为是死神的化身."
很酷吧？
Hence its handle, 'Death lncarnate."' Pretty cool, huh?
"它的神经性毒液是自然界中
"lts neurotoxic venom is one of nature's most effective poisons,
"毒性是最强的一种
能导致全身麻痹
. "acting on the nervous system, causing paralysis.
"它毒液能使人在4小时内死亡
"The venom of a black mamba can kill a human being in four hours
"不过那是咬到脚踝或是拇指
"if, say, bitten on the ankle or the thumb.
"然而，如果咬到脸或身体
"However, a bite to the face or torso
20分钟内就会从全身麻痹到死亡."
can bring death from paralysis within 20 minutes."
现在听好咯，因为和你有关
Now, you should listen to this, 'cause this concerns you.
"它咬一口所能释放出的毒液
"The amount of venom that can be delivered from a single bite
非常巨量."
can be gargantuan."
我一直都挺喜欢这个词，"巨量"
You know, I've always liked that word, "gargantuan."
平时说话很少有机会用得到
I so rarely have an opportunity to use it in a sentence.
"如果不即时用血清治疗
"lf not treated quickly with antivenom,
"10到15毫克就能致命
"ten to 1 5 milligrams can be fatal to human beings.
"然而黑曼巴一口…
"However, the black mamba can deliver
就能放出100到400毫克的毒液."
as much as 1 00 to 400 milligrams of venom from a single bite."
现在…
Now...
在你生命最后
几分钟的挣扎里
...in these last agonizing minutes of life you have left,
让我好好回答
你刚才提出的问题
Iet me answer that question you asked earlier more thoroughly.
此时此刻…
Right at this moment...
我感受最深的是婉惜
...the biggest "R" I feel is regret.
婉惜我所遇到
(或许是)最伟大的战士
Regret that maybe the greatest warrior I have ever met
怎么会死在像你
这样卑鄙无耻小人的手上
met her end at the hands of a bushwhackin', scrub, alkie, piece of shit like you.
那女人应该死的更壮烈才对
That woman deserved better.
比尔…
Bill...
我有个不幸的消息
...I have some tragic news.
你弟弟死了
Your brother's dead.
真遗憾，宝贝
I am so sorry, baby.
她在他住的活动屋里放了条黑曼巴
She put a black mamba in his camper.
我把事情解决了，她也死了
I got her, sweetie. She's dead.
这么说吧:
Let me put it this way:
如果你觉得很伤心，就去加州巴斯多
You ever start feeling sentimental, go to Barstow, California.
到了以后，去花店买一大束花
When you get here, walk into a florist and buy a bunch of flowers.
然后带着花去杭廷顿公墓
Then you take those flowers to Huntington Cemetery
再富乐和瓜达路培街交口
找一块叫做宝・休兹的墓碑
on Fuller and Guadalupe, look for the headstone marked "Paula Schultz,"
再把花放在墓上
and lay them on the grave.
那儿就是你的小乖
(碧翠丝・基多)安息的地方
'Cause you will be standing at the final resting place of Beatrix Kiddo.
- 玛缇・克超瑟？
- 在
- Marty Kitrosser? - Here.
- 美洛妮・贺豪斯？
- 在
- Melanie Harrhouse? - Here.
- 碧翠丝・基多？
- 在
- Beatrix Kiddo? - Here.
我可以四小时之内到
Look... I can be there in about four hours.
你要我过去吗？
Do you want me to come over?
不…不…
如果你要，宝贝，我立马过去
No, no, no, no. You need me, baby, I'm there.
好，我现在就出发
OK. I'm leaving now.
你先抽口大麻烟或什么的
我马上就到
You go smoke some pot or somethin', I'll be there soon.
恶心
Gross.
"献给我的弟弟，巴德
我唯一爱的人，比尔."
"T o my brother, Budd. The only man I ever loved. Bill."
那是什么？
What's that?
巴德的半藏刀
Budd's Hanzo sword.
他说他拿去当了
He said he pawned it.
那么他就是个骗子
Guess that makes him a liar now, don't it?
- 艾儿？
- 碧(翠丝)
- Elle? - Bea.
有件事情我一直很好奇
Somethin' I've always been curious about.
算是咱们女孩间的秘密吧…
Just between us girls...
你对白眉说了什么
他居然戳瞎了你一只眼睛？
...what did you say to Pai Mei to make him snatch out your eye?
我骂他可怜的老不死
I called him a miserable old fool.
噢～馊主意
Ooh. Bad idea.
猜猜我干了啥？
Know what I did?
我宰了那可怜的老不死
I killed that miserable old fool.
鱼头味道如何呀，可怜的老不死？
How do you like the fish head, you miserable old fool?
我在鱼头里下了毒
I poisoned his fish heads.
艾儿，你这条没人性的狗
Elle, you treacherous dog.
我一定会…
I - give - you - my - word --
我告诉他
And I told him,
"对我来说，你这老不死的话…
"T o me, the word of an old fool like you
一文不值."
is worth less than nothing."
没错
That's right.
我宰了你师父
I killed your master.
我现在还要杀你
And now I'm gonna kill you, too.
就用你自己的刀
With your own sword, no less.
再过一会儿，就成了我的刀了
Which, in the very immediate future, will become my sword.
婊子…
Bitch...
你马上就玩完了
...you don't have a future.
操你这婊子！
Fucking bitch!
臭婊子！
我宰了你！
你他妈的死定了！
I'll kill you! You're fuckin' dead!
你这婊子！ 你这婊子！
You bitch! You bitch!
我要宰了你，婊子
I'll fucking kill you, you bitch!
我逮得到你！
Oh, I'll get you!
我要…
I'm gonna...
你在哪儿？
让我操你！
Where are you? Lemme fuckin' at you!
你在哪儿？
我来了，你这臭婊子！
Where are you? I'm coming, you fucking bitch!
你死定了！ 死定了！
You're fucking dead! You're dead!
终章
终章：对决
就像很多从没见过
自己父亲的人一样
Like most men who never knew their father,
比尔喜欢有长者风范的人
Bill collected father figures.
第一个是 艾斯特邦・维黑欧
The first was Esteban Vihaio.
艾斯特邦是个淫媒
也是他母亲的朋友
Esteban was a pimp and a friend of Bill's mother.
他在墨西哥的阿库那
经营一家妓院超过50年了
He ran a brothel in Acuna, Mexico for over 50 years.
他的保镳团叫"阿库那小子"
His army, the Acuna Boys,
是那些妓女生的没爹的孩子
他们负责娼寮的生意
made up of the fatherless offspring of his whores, ran Acuna.
而他是他们的头儿
He ran the Acuna Boys.
他现在80岁了，就是这个
正在享受安逸的退休生活的人
Now, at the age of 80, it would be this retired gentleman of leisure
可以告诉我比尔在哪里
who could point me in Bill's direction.
是艾斯特邦・维黑欧先生吗？
Senor Esteban Vihaio?
正是
Yes.
我能叨扰一下吗？
May I join you?
如果你不连名带姓叫我
只叫我艾斯特邦，那就可以
Only on the condition that you call me Esteban.
- 艾斯特邦，我能叨扰一下吗？
- 请
- May I join you, Esteban? - Please.
美国人？
Americana?
是的
Yes.
如果你喜欢
我也会说一点西班牙语
I speak a little Spanish, if you prefer.
不…不…，我喜欢说英语
No, no, no, no. I prefer English.
我很久没说英语了
I haven't spoken it in a while,
尤其不能错过，能和像你这么漂亮
的小姐说话的机会
but I would relish the opportunity to converse with such a pretty companion as yourself.
能和像你这样的绅士做伴
才是我的荣幸
It's my pleasure to be in the company of such a fine gentleman as yourself.
我得提醒你，美丽的小姐…
I must warn you, young lady...
我是很容易被赞美冲昏头的
...I am susceptible to flattery.
我能帮你什么？
How may I be of service to you?
比尔在哪儿？
Where's Bill?
啊…
Ahh.
那你一定是碧翠丝了
You must be Beatrix.
难怪他喜欢你
I can see the attraction.
我认识比尔时他才五岁
我带他去看电影
I remember when Bill was only five years old, I took him to the movies.
是拉娜・图纳和约翰・嘉菲尔
It was a movie starring Lana Turner.
主演的"邮差总按两次铃"
The Postman Always Ring Twice, with John Garfields.
每当她出现在银幕上时
And whenever she would appear on the screen,
比尔就会情不自禁的吸允拇指
Bill would begin compulsively to suck his thumb to an obscene amount.
从那一刻起我就知道
这孩子会傻呼呼的迷恋金发美女
And I knew from this very moment, this boy was a fool for blonds.
你知道…
You know...
能像傻子一样
迷恋你这种金发美女…
...being a fool for a woman such as yourself...
也不是件坏事儿
...is always the right thing to do.
如果我在退休前结识你
If we had met when I was back in business...
你一定会成为我的头牌
...you would have been my number one lady.
- 过奖了
- 你一定会
- Well, I'm flattered. - You goddamn well better be.
这是？… 我听说你开的是小卡车
This... I heard you were driving a truck.
我的滦』醭祷盗
My Pussy Wagon died on me.
那滤懒耍
The Pussy died. Hmm.
比尔朝你头上开了一枪？
Bill shot you in the head, no?
是
- Yes. - Hmm.
如果是我，可不会那么狠
I would have been much nicer.
了不起让你破个相
I would have just cut your face.
对不起
You must forgive me.
请…和我喝一杯吧
Please... you have a drink with me.
克！
Clara! (smooches)
来了
Coming.
(西语)
Dos anejo.
谢谢
Gracias.
刚说到哪儿了？
What were we talking about?
比尔
Bill.
- 比尔在哪里？
- 比尔在哪里
- Where's Bill? - Where's Bill.
哦，嗯
Yeah. Hmm.
比尔在四季别墅
去萨尼那的路上
Bill is at the Villa Quatro, on the road to Salina.
我画个地图给你
I will draw you a map.
比尔就像我的儿子
Bill is like a son to me.
- 你知道我为什么帮助你吗？
- 不知道
- Do you know why I help you? - No.
因为这是他的意思
Because he would want me to.
这我可不相信
Now, that I don't believe.
不然他如何能再见到你？
How else is he ever going to see you again?
不许动，妈咪
Freeze, Mommy.
砰～砰～哦！
Bang, bang! Oh!
她打中我们了，宝贝！
Oh! She got us, B.B.
妈咪打中我们了！
哦，我要死了！
Mommy got us. Oh, I'm dying!
我要死了
I'm dying.
快趴下，甜心
妈咪击中我们了
Fall down, sweetheart. Mommy shot us.
但是，快枪手基多不知道的是
小宝贝只不过是装死而已，
But little did Quickdraw Kiddo know that little B.B. was only playing possum,
因为她实际上刀枪不入
due to the fact that she was impervious to bullets.
我刀枪不入，妈咪
I am pervious to bullets, Mommy.
嘿！躺下！
你在装死呢！
Hey, get back down there. You're playing possum.
当冷笑的杀手的走向
她认为已经饮弹身亡的尸体时
So, as the smirking killer advanced on what she thought was a bullet-ridden corpse,
这时候，小宝贝开枪了
that's when little B.B. fired.
砰～砰～！
Bang, bang!
你死了，妈咪！
快死呀！
You're dead, Mommy. So die.
哦！
Oh!
宝贝
B.B.
哦，宝贝…
Oh! B.B....
我早该料到…
I should've known.
你是…最棒的
You are... the best.
哦，妈咪，不要死！
Oh, Mommy. Don't die.
我只是玩游戏而已！
I was just playing.
我知道
I know.
我告诉她，你在睡觉
I told her that you were asleep...
但有一天你会醒来去找她
...but that one day you'd wake up and come back to her.
她问我："如果我出生时
妈咪就在睡觉…
And she asked me, "lf Mommy's been asleep since I was born,
她如何知道我长什么样呢？"
then how will she know what I look like?"
我回答说："因为妈咪一直梦见你啊！"
To which I replied, "Because Mommy's been dreaming of you."
我就是这么说的
That's what I said.
你有没有梦到我？
我有梦到你哦
Did you dream of me? I dreamed of you.
每天晚上，宝贝！
每天晚上！
Every single night, baby. Every single night.
我等你醒来等了好久，妈咪
I waited a long time for you to wake up, Mommy.
现在让我看看你
Now, let me look at you.
哦
Oh.
哇～哇～哇～
你真是个漂亮的小女生
My, my, my, what a pretty little girl you are.
你也很漂亮，妈咪
You're pretty too, Mommy.
告诉妈咪，我给你看她照片的时候，
你怎么说的？
Tell Mommy what you said when I showed you her picture.
说啊，别害羞
Come on, shy girl.
你一定记得的，快说啊
Come on. You know what you said.
快呀！告诉妈咪！
这会让她开心的！
Come on. Tell Mommy. It'll make her feel good. Come on.
对呀，快说
- Mnh-mnh. - Yeah. Come on.
我说…我说
I said... I said,
"我说你是我见过这世界上
最美丽的女人."
"You're the most beautifulest woman I ever saw in the whole wide world."
没错
她是这么说的
That's the truth. That's what she said.
宝贝，你是不是认为
妈咪的头发是世界上最漂亮的？
B.B., don't you think Mommy has the prettiest hair in the whole wide world?
- 对啊
- 实际上，比漂亮更漂亮
- Yes, I do. - Matter of fact, it's better than pretty.
- 比漂亮更漂亮，该怎么说？
- 嗯…美丽
- What's better than pretty? - Mmm... Gorgeous.
好极了. 美丽
妈咪很美丽
Very good. Gorgeous. Mommy is gorgeous.
你知道吗，甜心…
妈咪有点生爹地的气
Hmm. You know, sweetie, Mommy's kinda mad at Daddy.
为什么？你是个坏爹地吗？
Why, Daddy? Were you being a bad daddy?
恐怕是的
我以前是个很坏的爹地
I'm afraid I was. I was a real bad daddy.
我们的小女儿
某天学到了生死的涵义
Our little girl learned about life and death the other day.
告诉妈咪埃米利欧的事吧
Wanna tell Mommy about what happened to Emilio?
我杀了它
I killed him.
- 埃米利欧是她的金鱼
- 埃米利欧是我的金鱼
- Emilio was her goldfish. - Emilio was my goldfiss.
她跑到我的房间，手里拿着金鱼
哭着说…
She came running into my room, holding the fish in her hand and crying,
"爹地，爹地，埃米利欧死了."
"Daddy. Daddy. Emilio's dead."
我说，"真的吗？ 太令人伤心了
And I said, "Really? That's so sad.
它是怎么死的？"
How did he die?"
- 你说什么来着？
- 我踩到它了
- And what did you say? - I stepped on him.
实际上，小宝贝
当时你很技巧的说…
Actually, young lady, the words you so strategically used were,
我"不小心"踩到它了
"l accidentally stepped on him."
那我就问她…
To which I queried,
"你的小脚怎么会
不小心踩到鱼缸里去了呢？"
"And just how did your foot accidentally find its way into Emilio's fishbowl?"
她说，"不是…不是…
我是在地毯上踩到它的."
And she said, "No, no, no. Emilio was on the carpet when I stepped on him."
嗯…像是剧情的铺陈
Mmm. The plot thickens.
埃米利欧到底是怎么
跑到地毯上的呢？
"And just how did Emilio get on the carpet?"
妈咪，你会为她感到非常骄傲
And Mommy, you would've been so proud of her.
她没有说谎
She didn't lie.
她说她把埃米利欧
从鱼缸拿出来…
She said she took Emilio out of his bowl...
放到地毯上的
...and put him on the carpet.
埃米利欧在地毯上干嘛呢？
And what was Emilio doing on the carpet?
一直跳
Flapping.
- 然后你就踩到它了？
- 嗯
- And then you stomped on him. - Uh-huh.
你把脚移开时…
And when you lifted up your foot...
- …埃米利欧在做什么？
- 什么也没做
-...what was Emilio doing then? - Nothing.
它不跳了，对吗？
He stopped flapping, didn't he?
后来她告诉我…
She told me later...
当她移开脚时…
...that the second she lifted up her foot
看见埃米利欧不跳了的时候
她就明白自己做了什么
and saw Emilio not flapping, she knew what she had done.
这不正是一幅生死交织
完美的画面吗？
Is that not the perfect visual image of life and death?
地毯上跳动的金鱼
和地毯上不动的金鱼
A fish flapping on the carpet, and a fish not flapping on the carpet.
这么强烈的感，即使一个对生死
完全没概念的4岁孩子都懂
So powerful, even a four-year-old with no concept of life or death knew what it meant.
- 你爱埃米利欧，是吗？
- 嗯
- You loved Emilio, didn't you? - Uh-huh.
那么…我也爱妈咪
Well... I love Mommy, too.
但我对妈咪做了一件
和你对埃米利欧做的同样的事情
But I did to Mommy what you did to Emilio.
- 你踩了妈咪？
- 更糟糕
- You stomped on Mommy? - Worse.
我开枪打了妈咪
I shot Mommy.
不是像我们刚才那样玩的
Not pretend shooting like we were just doing.
我真的用枪打了她
I shot her for real.
为什么？
你是想知道会发生什么是吗？？
Why? Did you want to see what would happen?
不是. 我知道开枪打她
会有怎样的结果
No, I knew what would happen to Mommy if I shot her.
但我不知道我打了妈咪以后
自己会怎样？
What I didn't know was, when I shot Mommy, what would happen to me.
- 后来怎样？
- 我很伤心
- What happened? - I was very sad.
所以那时我学到了……
And that's when I learned...
有些事做了以后
就无法再改变了
...some things, once you do, they can never be undone.
- 妈咪后来怎么样了？
- 你怎么不问妈咪呢？
- What happened to Mommy? - Why don't you ask Mommy?
妈咪，你没事吧？
疼不疼？
You OK, Mommy? Did it hurt?
不疼，甜心
No, sweetie.
不再疼了
Doesn't hurt anymore.
会使你生病吗？
Did it make you sick?
不会. 我只是让我睡着了
No. It made me sleep.
所有没能陪你，我在睡觉
That's why I haven't been with you, B.B. I've been asleep.
但你现在醒了，对吧，妈咪？
But you're awake now, Mommy. Right?
是啊，我全醒了，小美人
I'm wide awake, pretty girl.
宝贝，你要妈咪睡前
陪你看录相片吗？
B.B., would you like Mommy to watch a video with you before sleepy time?
嗯
Uh-huh.
妈咪，你愿意陪我
在睡前看录相片吗？
Mommy, do you wanna watch a video with me before sleepy time?
哦，当然，我愿意
Oh, yeah! I would love to.
- 你要看哪一片呢？
- 幕府杀手
- Which one do you wanna watch? - Shogun Assassin.
不好，宝贝，那片子太长了
No, B.B. Shogun Assassin is too long.
- 嗯
- 不长.
- Mnh-mnh. - No, it's not.
那好吧，小姐们，我失陪了
Well, then, I'll leave you ladies to it.
我小时候，我爸爸很有名
(boy) When I was little, my father was famous.
他是全帝国家最好的武士
He was the greatest samurai in the empire.
他是幕府将军的刽子手
And he was the shogun's decapitator.
曾经砍掉131个诸侯的脑袋
He cut off the heads of 131 lords.
当我爸爸回到家看见妈妈时
他就会忘记那些杀戮
My father would come home to Mother and when he would see her, he would forget about the killings.
他不怕将军，将军却怕他
He wasn't scared of the shogun, but the shogun was scared of him.
也许那就是问题所在
Maybe that was the problem.
一天晚上….将军派出了…
One night, the shogun sent...
(@ "About Her" by Malcolm McLaren)
# 我男人的心 #
@ My man got a heart
# 像海里的石头 #
@ Like the rock that's in the sea
# 没人告诉我她的事 #
@ Well, no one told me about her
# 她是如何死的 #
@ The way she lied
# 没人告诉我她的事 #
@ Well, no one told me about her
# 多少人在哭泣 #
@ How many people cried
# 我男人的心 #
@ My man got a heart
# 像海里的石头 #
@ Like the rock that's in the sea
# 我男人的心 #
@ My man got a heart
# 像海里的石头 #
@ Like the rock that's in the sea
# 没人告诉我她的事 #
@ Well, no one told me about her
# 她是如何死的 #
@ The way she lied
# 没人告诉我她的事 #
@ Well, no one told me about her
# 多少人在哭泣 #
@ How many people cried
# 即使难过也太晚了 #
@ But it's too late to say you're sorry
# 我怎会知道 #
@ How would I know?
# 我为何在乎 #
@ Why should I care?
# 不必再去找寻她 #
@ Please don't bother trying to find her
# 她不在那儿 #
@ She's not there
我正在欣赏你的刀
I was just admiring your sword.
真是把好刀
Quite a piece of work.
说到这儿…半藏最近如何？
Speaking of which, how is Hanzo-san?
他很好
He's good.
他的寿司愈做愈好了吗？
Has his sushi gotten any better?
我简直难以相信
他居然替你铸刀
You know, I couldn't believe it. You got him to make you a sword.
其实很简单
我只是提到了你的名字，比尔
It was easy. I just dropped your name, Bill.
哈…那就够了
That'd do it.
# 没人告诉我她的事 #
@ Well, no one told me about her
那么我们该用
半藏的刀来交手，对吧？
I suppose the idea is we cross Hanzo swords. Am I right?
嗯
Well,
正巧这个庄园有片私人海滩
it just so happens this hacienda has its own private beach.
海滩沐浴在月光下
显得特别的非常美丽
And that private beach just so happens to look particularly beautiful bathed in moonlight.
今天碰巧又是满月
And there just so happens to be a full moon out tonight.
如果你愿意咱们就
去海滩用刀决斗
So, swordfighter, if you want a swordfight, that's where I suggest.
但是如果你想用传统的方式…
But if you wanna be old school about it..
你知道我是最传统的
...and you know I'm all about old school...
那就等到天亮后
再像正统武士道一般对决
...then we could wait until dawn and slice each other up at sunrise
就像一对真的夫妻似的…
Iike a couple of real-life honest...
现在…如果你不冷静一下
我就在你膝盖上来一枪
Now, if you don't settle down, I'm gonna have to put one in your kneecap.
现在…如果你不冷静一下
我就在你膝盖上来一枪
And I hear tell that's a very painful place to get shot in.
哈哈哈～，我只是跟你闹着玩的
I'm just fuckin' with you.
现在…
Now...
至于你…
...when it comes to you...
至于我们…
...and us...
我有些不明白的地方
...I have a few unanswered questions.
在这个血腥的复仇故事
达到最高潮之前…
So, before this tale of bloody revenge reaches its climax,
我要问你几个问题
你得照实回答我
I'm gonna ask you some questions, and I want you to tell me the truth.
然而…这也有矛盾
However, therein lies a dilemma.
因为一谈到到我
我相信你不能也不会对我说实话
Because when it comes to the subject of me, I believe you are truly and utterly incapable of telling the truth.
特别是对我
甚至你不愿意对自己说实话
Especially to me. And least of all, to yourself.
同时…只要一谈到我…
And when it comes to the subject of me,
我不能也不会相信你所说的
I am truly and utterly incapable of believing anything you say.
你认为该怎么解决这个矛盾？
How do you suppose we solve this dilemma?
哦…
Well,
我突然想到
it just so happens,
一个解决办法
I have a solution.
- 啊！
- 打中了！
- Aah! - Gotcha!
该死！
Goddamn!
妈的，你用什么射我？
What the fuck did you just shoot me with?
是我最伟大的发明
起码是我最喜欢的
My greatest invention. Or at least my favorite.
别碰它，不然我会在
你脸夹上再来一枪
Don't touch it, or I'll stick another one right in your cheek.
你中的子弹里有一种物质
现正开始在你血管里流窜
What lies within that dart, just begging to course its way through your veins...
是一种非常强而有效的麻醉剂
它能让人说实话
...is an incredibly potent and quite infallible truth serum.
我称它做"毋庸怀疑的事实"
I call it "The Undisputed Truth."
比有钠成分的麻醉剂还要强两倍
Twice as strong as sodium pentothal, with no druggie aftereffects.
除了会让你有点儿快感之外
没有其他副作用. 感觉到了吗？
Except for a slight wave of euphoria. You feel it?
- 快感？
- 对
- Euphoria? - Yeah.
- 不
- 真糟糕
- No. - Too bad.
你知道…
As you know...
我很喜欢漫画
...I'm quite keen on comic books.
特别是那些关于超级大英雄的
Especially the ones about superheroes.
我对那些英雄式的神话非常着迷
I find the whole mythology surrounding superheroes fascinating.
拿我最喜欢的超人为例吧
Take my favorite superhero, Superman.
虽然不算好漫画，也画的不好…
Not a great comic book. Not particularly well-drawn.
嗯
Mmm.
但就神话上的意义来说
But the mythology...
他不仅伟大，而且是独一无二的
The mythology is not only great, it's unique.
这捞什子的药性多久会发作？
How long does this shit take to go into effect?
大约两分钟吧
正好够我讲完重点了
About two minutes. Just long enough for me to finish my point.
英雄式的神话中都有个特点
他们同时是英雄也是凡人
Now, a staple of the superhero mythology is, there's the superhero and there's the alter ego.
蝙蝠侠原来是布鲁斯・伟恩
蜘蛛侠原来是彼得・派克
Batman is actually Bruce Wayne, Spider-Man is actually Peter Parker.
当蜘蛛侠早上醒来，他是彼得・派克
When that character wakes up in the morning, he's Peter Parker.
他得穿上蜘蛛服才会变成蜘蛛侠
He has to put on a costume to become Spider-Man.
从这个观点来说，超人是更出众的
And it is in that characteristic Superman stands alone.
他不是后来变成超人的
Superman didn't become Superman.
而是天生的
Superman was born Superman.
超人早上醒来，他就是个超人
When Superman wakes up in the morning, he's Superman.
他的凡人面是克拉克・肯特
His alter ego is Clark Kent.
他衣服上的大红"S"
His outfit with the big red "S" -
是当他父母
发现他时，原本就在包着他的毛毯上
that's the blanket he was wrapped in as a baby when the Kents found him.
那是他自己的衣服
Those are his clothes.
至于眼镜和西装，只是他
为了要融入凡人社会中而穿的
What Kent wears - the glasses, the business suit - that's the costume. That's the costume Superman wears to blend in with us.
克拉克・肯特只是
超人眼中我们的化身
Clark Kent is how Superman views us.
至于克拉克・肯特的个性…
And what are the characteristics of Clark Kent?
他软弱…
He's weak...
缺乏自信…
...he's unsure of himself...
他是个懦夫
...he's a coward.
克拉克・肯特是超人
对全人类的所下的定义
Clark Kent is Superman's critique on the whole human race.
有点儿像碧翠丝・基多和
汤米・普林顿的夫人
Sorta like Beatrix Kiddo and Mrs. Tommy Plimpton.
原来如此
Aso.
总算你说出了重点
The point emerges.
你原本可以成维爱琳・普林顿的
You would've worn the costume of Arlene Plimpton.
不过你生来就是碧翠丝・基多
But you were born Beatrix Kiddo.
你每天早上醒来
还是碧翠丝基多
And every morning when you woke up, you'd still be Beatrix Kiddo.
你可以把针头拔出来了
Oh, you can... take the needle out.
你叫我超级英雄？
Are you calling me a superhero?
我叫你杀手…
I'm calling you a killer.
天生的杀手
A natural born killer.
你一直都是…以后永远都是
You always have been, and you always will be.
搬去艾帕索…
Moving to El Paso...
二手唱片行打工…
...working in a used record store...
和汤米一起去看电影…
...goin' to the movies with Tommy...
收集折价券
...clipping coupons.
那只不过是你…
That's you...
你想伪装成工蜂…
...trying to disguise yourself as a worker bee.
躲在蜂巢里不被发现罢了
That's you tryin' to blend in with the hive.
但你不是工蜂
But you're not a worker bee.
你是变节的杀人蜂
You're a renegade killer bee.
不管你喝多少啤酒
吃过多少烤肉
And no matter how much beer you drank or barbecue you ate
或是你的屁股变得多肥
or how fat your ass got,
世上一切都不能改变这个事实
nothing in the world would ever change that.
第一个问题:
First question:
你真的认为，从此能在艾帕索
过个普通人的生活吗？
Did you really think your life in El Paso was gonna work?
不！
No!
但宝贝本来是我的！
But I would've had B.B.!
别误会我的意思
Don't get me wrong.
我认为你本来就会是个好母亲
I think you would have been a wonderful mother.
但你也是个杀手
But you are a killer.
你能找到我之前所杀的那些人
也都是高手，对吧？
All those people you killed to get to me...
感觉不错，对吧？
...felt damn good, didn't they?
对
Yes.
每一个人都是吧？
Every single one of them?
对
Yes.
那是给你暖身的
That was the warmup round.
现在到了要问你
值六万四千美元的问题了
Now comes the $64,000 question.
你为什么要离开我
还怀着我的孩？
Why did you run away from me with my baby?
你记得你给最后的一个任务吗？
Do you remember the last assignment you sent me on?
当然
Of course.
王丽莎
Lisa Wong.
出发的那天早上，我病了
The morning I left, I was sick.
我在飞机上吐了
On the plane, I threw up.
我开始想:
So I started thinking:
我可能是怀孕了
Maybe I was pregnant.
使用方便，打开盖子
将尿液浸泡5分钟
"Easy to use. Remove cap and urinate on the absorbent end for five seconds.
只要90秒，小窗口上
就会显示正确结果
"Accurate results in only 90 seconds. You can read the results as soon as the line appears in the window."
妈的
Fuck.
我不知道的是…
What I didn't know...
旅途中我的踪迹已经败露
...was that somewhere on my journey I had been spotted.
我到了洛杉矶不久
王丽莎就派出了杀手
With me in L.A., it didn't take Lisa Wong long to send an assassin of her own.
哈，有事儿吗？
-  Hello, can I help you?
哈，我是金凯伦饭
诚志饭店的客服经理
Hello, I'm Karen Kim. I'm the hospitality manager of the hotel.
我们有个见面礼给您
I have a welcome gift from the management.
真周到
Oh, that's nice. Um...
留在门下就好
Can you just leave it by the door?
- 你很会使长枪吗？
- 不是非得这么近我能才打中你
- You pretty good with that shotgun? - Not that I have to be at this range,
我可是个使枪老手.
but I'm a fuckin' surgeon with this shotgun.
告诉你吧，婊子，我比神枪手
奥克丽还准，你在我射程内
Well, guess what, bitch? I'm better than Annie Oakley.
- 我的枪正瞄准着你
- 我能把你的猪脑袋轰掉
- And I got you right in my sight. - I could blow your fuckin' head off.
不会比我打中你的眉心快
咱们还是谈谈吧
Not before I put one right between your eyes, so let's talk.
凯伦…
Karen...
我刚发现…
...I just found out...
现在…
...right now...
就在你刚破门而入后…
...not a moment before you blew a hole through the door...
- …我怀孕了
- 说这干嘛？
-...that I'm pregnant. - What is this?
门边的地上…
On the floor by the door...
有个验孕器
上面显示我怀孕了
...is a strip that says I'm pregnant.
鬼扯！
Bullshit.
换做别时，你一定没错
Any other time you'd be 100 percent right.
但这次…
This time...
你完全错了
...you're 100 percent wrong.
我是世上能要人命的女人…
I'm the deadliest woman in the world.
但现在…
But right now...
有了孩子我却怕了
...I'm just scared shitless for my baby.
求你！
Please.
看一下验孕器
Just look at the strip.
求你！
Please.
待在原地别动
Stay where you are and don't move.
妈的，我不懂这表示啥？
I don't know what this fuckin' shit means.
说明就在盒子上啊！
The box with the directions - it's right there.
使用方便
"Easy to use.
打开盖子
将尿液浸泡海绵处5分钟
Remove the cap and urinate on the absorbent end."
蓝色代表怀孕
Blue means pregnant.
我自己会读，不用你多事
I'll read it myself, thank you.
哦，好
Oh, OK.
好吧，如果我相信你
下面该怎么做？
Say I were to believe you. What then?
你回家吧
Just go home.
我也回家
I'll do the same.
恭喜你！
Congratulations.
在验孕器变蓝色前…
Before that strip turned blue...
我是个女人，我是你的女人
...I was a woman, I was your woman.
我是你的杀手…为你而杀
I was a killer who killed for you.
在验孕器变成蓝色前
我愿意以从摩托车上…
Before that strip turned blue, I would've jumped a motorcycle
跳到高速飞驰的火车上
onto a speeding train.
为了你
For you.
一但验孕器变蓝色以后…
But once that strip turned blue...
我再也无法做那些事了
...I could no longer do any of those things.
再也不能了
Not anymore.
因为我要做妈妈了
Because I was gonna be a mother.
你能了解吗？
Can you understand that?
能
Yes.
但你为什么不…
But why didn't you...
当时告诉我，反而是现在？
...tell me then, instead of now?
你一旦知道，她就是你的了
Once you knew, you'd claim her.
我不希望那样
And I didn't want that.
这不是你能决定的
Not your decision to make.
我能
Yes.
是我为我女儿所做的正确决定
But it's the right decision, and I made it for my daughter.
她来到的世界应该是清白的
She deserved to be born with a clean slate.
但是和你在一起
But with you...
她就会生在一个她不该在的世界
...she would've been born into a world she shouldn't have.
我必须作选择
I had to choose.
我选择了她
I chose her.
你知道…如果5年前
You know, five years ago,
要我列出绝不可能发生事情的清单
if I had to make a list of impossible things that could never happen,
你在我的脑壳上来一枪…
you performing a coup de grace on me by bustin' a cap in my crown...
绝对会排在第一位
...would've been right at the top of the list.
但是我错了，不是吗？
I'd have been wrong, wouldn't l?
对不起
I-I'm sorry.
那是个问我的问题吗？
Was that a question?
如果说你认为那是不可能发生的事
这样说的话，你是错了
Of impossible things that could never happen - yes, in this instance, you would've been wrong.
那么？
Well?
当你没回来…
When you never came back,
我当然会想到王丽莎
或者其他什么人杀了你
I naturally assumed Lisa Wong, or somebody else, had killed you.
哦，说正格儿的…
Oh! And for the record...
如果你没死
却让爱你的人误会你死了
...Ietting somebody think somebody they love is dead when they're not
是非常残酷的
is quite cruel.
我为你伤心了三个月
I mourned you for three months.
在我痛苦的第三个月
And in the third month of mourning you...
我发现了你的踪迹
...I tracked you down.
我不是故意要去追查你的行踪
I wasn't tryin' to track you down.
而是在追查
是找哪个混蛋杀了你
I was tryin' to track down the fucking assholes I thought killed you.
结果我却找到你了
So I find you...
结果我发现什么？
...and what do I find?
你不仅没死…
Not only are you not dead...
还要嫁给一个该死的混蛋
...you're getting married to some fucking jerk.
而且你还怀孕了
And you're pregnant.
我…反应过度了些
I overreacted.
反应过度？ 这就是你的解释？
You overreacted? Is that your explanation?
我没说我要解释什么！
I didn't say I was gonna explain myself.
我只是要告诉你实话
I said I was gonna tell you the truth.
如果我说的太复杂
我就再说明白点
But if that's too cryptic, let's get literal.
我是个杀手
I'm a killer.
我是个杀人的混蛋…你是知道的
I'm a murdering bastard. You know that.
如果你伤了这个混蛋的心
就会有很严重的后果
And there are consequences to breaking the heart of a murdering bastard.
这你也曾经历过
You experienced some of them.
我的反应真的
那么出乎你的预料吗？
Was my reaction really that surprising?
是的…没错
Yes. It was.
你真能做出那种事吗…
Could you do what you did?
你当然能
Of course you could.
可我没想到你居然忍心那样对我
But I never thought you would, or could, do that to me.
我真的很抱歉，小乖
I'm really sorry, Kiddo...
但是你想错了
...but you thought wrong.
你我之间还有未了结的账
You and I have unfinished business.
宝贝…我知道你不是在开玩笑
Baby... you ain't kiddin'.
白眉真的教你五指穿心掌？
Pai Mei taught you the Five-Point-Palm Exploding-Heart Technique?
当然
'Course he did.
你为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
不知道
I don't know.
因为我是…
Because I'm...
是个坏人
...a bad person.
不
No.
你不是坏人
You're not a bad person.
你是个了不起的人
You're a terrific person.
是我最喜欢的人
You're my favorite person.
但偶尔…
But every once in a while...
你还真像个婊子
...you can be a real cunt.
我气色如何？
How do I look?
你像已经准备好了
You look ready.
[第二天早晨]
呵～呵～呵～
像朵"小"花吧！
Well, well, well. If it ain't the little flower.
美国人民大家晚安，一切就绪
(narrator) Good evening, Mr. and Mrs. America and all the ships at sea.
现在报导新闻. (闪光灯)
Let's go to press. Flash.
你家里有喜鹊吗？
Do you have a magpie in your home?
如果有，那你是最幸运的了
If you do, you are most fortunate.
喜鹊是全世界最迷人的鸟
The magpie is the most charming bird in all the world.
也是农夫们最好的朋友
He is the best friend a farmer ever had.
对他要温柔，对他要仁慈
Treat him gently. Treat him kindly.
永远记住…喜鹊值得你尊敬
And always remember, the magpie deserves your respect.
谢谢你
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
哦，谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
现在我要告诉你，我要做什么
(magpie) Now, I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
我头不疼
I ain't got no headache.
老兄，你当然头疼
(magpie) Oh yes you have, brother.
(西语歌曲)
(@ male sings in Spanish)
(@ "Goodnight Moon" by Shivaree)
# 门上有根钉子 #
@ There's a nail in the door
# 草地上有玻璃 #
@ And there's glass on the lawn
# 门闩好 电视开着 #
@ Tacks on the floor, and the TV is on
# 我总是带着枪睡觉 #
@ And I always sleep with my guns
# 当你不在时 #
@ When you're gone
# 我床头有把刀 #
@ There's a blade by the bed
# 电话在我手上 #
@ And a phone in my hand
# 地上有只狗 #
@ A dog on the floor
# 床头柜里有钱 #
@ And some cash on the nightstand
# 当我独自一人时 就停止作梦 #
@ When I'm all alone, the dreaming stops
# 我实在无法忍受 #
@ And I just can't stand
# 我该怎么办 我不过是个孩子 #
@ What should I do? I'm just a little baby
# 如果电灯坏了 还有也许 #
@ What if the lights go out and maybe
# 然后风吹的呼呼叫 #
@ And then the wind just starts to moan
# 他跟踪我到家门口 #
@ Outside the door, he followed me home
# 月儿晚安，我要太阳 #
Well, goodnight moon, I want the sun
# 如果还不天亮 我可能就完了 #
@ If it's not here soon, I might be done
# 如果我不说月儿晚安
就不会很快天亮 #
@ No, it won't be too soon 'til I say goodnight moon
# 但是月儿高挂 又怎么救得了我 #
@ Well, you're up so high, how can you save me?
# 当今夜黑暗降临 #
@ When the dark comes here tonight
# 带我过前厅到床边 #
@ To take me up to my front walk and into bed
# 在那儿亲吻我的脸
吃掉我的头 #
@ Where it kisses my face and eats my head
# 我该怎么办 我不过是个孩子 #
@ What should I do? I'm just a little baby
# 如果电灯坏了 还有也许 #
@ What if the lights go out and maybe
# 然后风吹的呼呼叫 #
@ And then the wind just starts to moan
# 他跟踪我到家门口 #
@ Outside the door, he followed me home
# 月儿晚安，我要太阳 #
@ Now, goodnight moon, I want the sun
# 如果还不天亮 我可能就完了 #
@ If it's not here soon, I might be done
# 如果我不说月儿晚安
就不会很快天亮 #
@ No, it won't be too soon 'til I say goodnight moon
# 如果我不说月儿晚安
就不会很快天亮 #
@ No, it won't be too soon 'til I say goodnight moon
开拍
And, action!
停
Cut.
哦，别啦
再来一次吧
Oh, come on. Let's do it again.